是的  我想叫辆车去伊顿微技术实验室
Yeah, I need a taxi to take me to Eaton Microtech Labs.
不  我不是本地人
Oh, I'm not from here.
你能让那个叫法国名的男人替我叫车吗
Can you get the guy with the French name on that?
对对  就是礼宾员
Yeah, yeah, yeah, Mr. Concierge.
华尔街季刊
卡迪夫在个人电脑市场投下大赌注
活过来啦  活啦  它活啦
It's alive, it's alive, it's alive.
你今早能回家太好了  谢谢你
I really appreciate you coming home this morning. Thank you.
我还得洗个澡刮刮脸赶紧去上班
I gotta shower and shave and get back to the office.
我是想让你看看这个
I just wanted to bring you this.
华尔街季刊
-文中多处引述了你的话  -你是说
- You were quoted several times. - Oh, you mean...
引述了"苏珊·费尔柴德"的话吗
"Susan Fairchild" Was quoted?
-法式吐司  今天什么日子  -我爸的生日
- French toast. What's the occasion? - Dad's birthday.
我还以为你是特地回家祝寿呢
I thought that's why you came home.
你送给他一支球杆
You got him a putter.
瞧瞧  什么风把你刮回来了
Well, well, well. Look what the cat dragged in.
生日快乐
Happy birthday.
他可喜欢你送的球杆了
He loves the putter.
你道谢了吗  亲爱的
Did you thank him, sweetheart?
今天跟我去俱乐部打一局吧
You should come to the club with me today. Play a quick nine?
我...还得上班去呢
Um, I gotta-- I got work I gotta do.
早上好啊  女儿们
Good morning, girls.
两天没见我了
Hey, no hello for Daddy,
都不跟爸爸打招呼吗
who you haven't seen in almost two days?
爸爸好
Hi, Daddy.
我们能带这个上学去吗
Can we take this to school?
-是计算器吗  -不  是电视
- Is it a calculator? - No, it's a TV.
你说这小玩意多厉害
Isn't that thing incredible?
是啊  这下可以整天黏在电视上了
Yeah, now they can watch TV all the time.
我刚和华族签了份独家协议
I just arranged an exclusive deal with Kazoku
把这玩意收进我们的秋季新品目录里
to carry them in our fall catalogue.
祝我生日快乐  是吧
Happy birthday to me, right?
你的电脑和IBM  XT相比怎么样
Well, how will your computer compare to the IBM XT?
我们的电脑不仅有IBM的全部优点
Ours has all the same features as the XT,
还另有额外的优势
plus-- plus a few bonus extras.
-比如呢  -比如
- Like what? - Like what?
比如你能带着这电脑去开房
Like you can haul it down to the no-tell motel
一边干你的秘书
when you screw your secretary
一边打你的备忘录
and you'd still get your memos typed up.
就比如这个
"Like what?"
你要是想拿IBM电脑玩这套
You try that with an IBM PC,
当心闪了老腰
hell, you'd throw out your back.
说说你们电脑的速度吧
Now, what about speed?
我们的顾客似乎只关心这个
That seems to be all our customers care about.
-我听说你们正在鼓捣286  -嗯
- I heard you guys were flirting with the 286. - Yeah.
我只是个纽约来的投机客
Oh, I'm just a carpetbagger from New York.
他们才不会信我
They won't listen to me.
先生们  我想所有的相关参数
Gentlemen, I think-- I think all the specs
都在你们手中的资料集里了
are right there in those packets that we gave you.
你们都认字吧
Y'all can read, right?
首先  我要澄清一下
First of all, to clarify,
包养小秘的费用不包括在电脑售价里
secretary isn't included at that price.
至于具体参数  我们的确在拿286试验
As for the specs, we were experimenting with the 286,
但如果真用286  你们的顾客得卖肾了
but in the end, it would only cost your customers an arm and a leg,
所以我们要用8兆赫兹的8086处理器
so we're going with an eight megahertz 8086.
这样不仅速度比市面上的产品快一倍
That's almost twice as fast as any PC on the market,
我们还集成了浮点运算协处理器
plus we're including a floating-point math coprocessor
其性能足以把IBM所有产品甩出几条街
that will run circles around any IBM PC.
我不妨开门见山
Let's cut to the chase
直截了当地回答你们想问的问题
and get to the question you came here to have answered.
而你们的总裁也会在
The question your CEO
计算机分销商展览后的会议上问这个问题
will ask you at your post-COMDEX powwow.
"第三排货架上该摆什么货"
"What do we put on our third shelf?"
不是第一排  那是留给IBM的
Not the first shelf-- that's reserved for IBM.
甚至不是第二排
Not even the second shelf.
那是留给你们的品牌电脑的
That's where your name brand computer goes.
就是在台湾组装  再贴上你们标签的电脑
The ones you have manufactured in Taiwan and slap your insignia on.
我说的是第三排
The third shelf.
杂牌电脑
The "Kludge" Shelf.
连理货勤杂工都不看好
The shelf your stock boys detest...
因为那些电脑太笨重
because the computers are so heavy...
又放在那么下面
and the shelves are so low.
那才是我们的位置
That's the shelf we're talking about.
这才是我们这些笨蛋的市场  对吗
That's the shelf us schmucks are aiming for, am I right?
不对
Wrong.
这不是一款IBM兼容克隆机
This isn't an IBM compatible clone.
这是新的兼容机
This is the new compatible.
IBM到时候得模仿我们
IBM will have to clone us.
把这话转达给你们总裁  我保证明年这时候
Tell that to your CEO and I promise you this time next year,
坐在总裁位子上的就是你们  问着
you'll be sitting in his chair asking,
我们在第三排架子上放什么
"What do we put on our third shelf?"
欢迎回来  旅行愉快吗
Welcome back. How was your trip?
-这都谁啊  -新来的软件工程师
- Who are all these people? - New team of software engineers.
这位是史蒂夫  软件开发部经理
This is Steve, our software development manager.
史蒂夫  这是卡梅伦
Steve, this is Cameron.
你的事我都跟他们说过了
I told them all about you.
但你没说她是女的
You didn't tell me she was a girl.
我就知道以你敏锐的分析能力一定猜得到
I knew your keen analytical skills would sniff it out.
把这些拿给戈登
Run those to Gordon.
我自己就能搞定所有软件
Look, I can handle all the software myself.
我在飞机上都设计好了
I already mapped out the design on the plane.
谁让你做的
Who told you to do that?
没谁  我只是以为...
No one. I thought that --
你以为这种大工程都怎么开展啊
Why? How do you think a project this big works?
在博斯沃思许可的范围内  人越多越好
Throwing as many people at the problem as Bosworth will approve.
你让我去辛辛那提旅游
Wait, did you send me to Cincinnati
就是为了
so that you could hire
背着我雇史蒂夫和他的小仆从吗
Steve and his little minions behind my back?
你想多了
Don't be paranoid.
我让你去辛辛那提是因为你需要休息
I sent you to Cincinnati 'cause you needed the rest.
写BIOS代码差点把你累死
Writing the BIOS almost killed you.
你们起好名字了吗
Have you guys thought of a name yet?
我打算在阿拉莫  死星和乔治里选一个
I'm deciding between "Alamo," "Death Star," And "George."
德州地名
出自《星球大战》
《星球大战》导演
真不敢相信你们居然不喜欢可汗I can't believe you guys don't like "Khan."
出自《星际迷航》
可汗
"Khan!"
抱歉
Excuse me?
BIOS代码是我写的  所以该我起名
I wrote the BIOS. I name it.
拉芙蕾丝
"Lovelace."
不是琳达·拉芙蕾丝  变态
Not Linda Lovelace, you pervs,
色情片《深喉》的女演员
是艾达·拉芙蕾丝Ada Lovelace.
诗人拜伦之女  生卒于19世纪
史上第一个电脑程序设计员
As in the first computer programmer ever?
为查尔斯·巴贝其的分析机编写算法  后被视为最早的计算机程序
好名字
Good name.
我们开机吧
All right, let's turn this baby on.
喝香槟喽
Champagne.
-喝香槟  -干的好
- Champagne. - Good work.
大家庆祝什么呢  屏幕都没亮啊
Why is everyone celebrating? The screen didn't even turn on.
-没有屏幕啊  -我们还没完全弄好呢
- There is no screen. - We're getting there.
我刚向一屋零售商许诺一台公文包大小的电脑
I just promised a room full of retailers a briefcase.
这堆破烂连运动包都塞不下
You couldn't fit this crap in a gym bag.
你的许诺是夸张的空头支票
You mean overpromised.
做一份只用动嘴不用动手的
It must be nice to have a job where you get to say words
工作一定挺惬意的吧
without having to actually do anything.
我来之前你卖出去过一台电脑吗
Did you ever sell a computer before I showed up here?
你们谁办到过吗
Did any of you?
我们该赶紧关了
Well, we should probably turn it off.
好像开始冒烟了
I think it's starting to smoke.
那就关吧  斯坦
Then turn it off, Stan.
这是什么
What the hell is this?
我要的是故障分析报告
I asked you to do a failure analysis report.
我做了啊
I did.
怎么回事  让我看看行吗
I don't understand. Can I see that?
在这儿  混在我写的补充报告里了
It's here. It got mixed up with the supplemental report I did.
好  谢了
Okay, thanks.
下次把我需要的报告放在最上面
Next time, just make sure the report I need is on top.
卡迪夫电子便携个人电脑  工作随时随地
如果去掉风扇  就会有散热问题
If we get rid of fans, we have a heat problem.
如果去掉协处理器  浮点运算速度就会下降
If we get rid of the coprocessor, we lose floating-point speed.
能减轻机身重量
That'll get weight out of the case.
至多就能减轻一两磅
That'll give us one, two pounds max.
乔想把重量减掉10磅
Joe wants this to be 10 pounds lighter.
我还希望我老婆减掉10磅呢
Yeah, I want my wife to be 10 pounds lighter.
生活不就得妥协
Life is about compromise.
我不是开玩笑  艾德
This isn't a joke, Ed.
一切都指着我们造好这台电脑呢
Everything is riding on us getting this right.
不做成谁都不许走  明白吗
And no one's leaving here until we do, you got that?
好诶  流浪者队得分
Yes. Rangers scored.
-表给我  -放松
- Give me that watch. - Ow, relax.
你想像布莱恩那样
Would you rather be pounding Shiners
下午3点就喝啤酒吗
with Brian at 3:00 in the afternoon?
我可以给你安排
'Cause that can be arranged.
抱歉
I'm sorry.
要是我们把显像管显示器换成液晶显示器呢
What if we swapped out the CRT for an LCD?
液晶屏更轻便
It's lighter and smaller.
但远远超出预算
And way over our budget.
找关系就不会
Not if you know a guy.
卡梅伦·豪伊
你好啊
What's up?
我是莱夫  那位是肯尼斯
I'm Lev. That's Kenneth,
不过大家都叫他悠悠球
but everyone calls him Yo-Yo.
-你在打游戏吗  -老天  你干什么啊
- Are you playing games? - Jesus, do you mind?
我给你的任务是写打印驱动程序  不是玩游戏
I assigned you to write print drivers, not play games.
-什么  什么时候的事  -你没看分工表吗
- What, when? - Well, didn't you check the flowchart?
我分配了所有的子程序任务
I mapped out all the subroutine assignments
以及完成任务的顺序
and which order to do them in.
打印驱动是边角料  我为什么不能做编译器
Print drivers are remedial. Why aren't I working on a compiler?
因为我已经有个团队在做了  这是其一
Because I already have a team on it, number one.
第二  据说代码存档的事不能交给你
Number two, I hear you can't be trusted to document your code,
第三  你得把自己的代码好好存档
and, number three, I need you to document your code.
欢迎来到衰人俱乐部
Welcome to the short bus.
是《巨洞冒险》吗
Is that "Adventure"?
76年研发的首款支持存档的文字冒险游戏
对
Yeah.
不出所料
Classic.
一听你敲键盘就猜来了
I could tell by your keystrokes.
那玩意上瘾的
That thing's heroin.
期末考前一晚逃了研讨班打游戏
Took out my graduate seminar the night before our final.
结果全部挂科
We all flunked.
悠悠球  我要把这个放在主机上
Hey, Yo-Yo, I'm putting this up on the mainframe,
跟你说一声啊
so consider yourself warned.
出来得正是时候
Perfect time for you to come out.
周末长假  所以这儿很空
This place empties out for the long weekend.
不会影响别人的比赛
You won't slow down anyone's game.
你给孩子们买的华族表真是个好礼物
That was a really nice gift you got the girls, the Kazoku watch.
我知道你觉得我宠坏她们了
I know you think I spoil them.
没有  你就该宠她们
No, no, you should spoil them.
看来你和华族电子的人
It sounds like you got a really good relationship
关系很不错啊
with the guys over at Kazoku Electronics.
我只想让你引见一下
Look, all I'm asking for is an introduction.
我需要给我的电脑配一块新液晶屏
I need a new LCD screen for my computer
华族的技术水平最高
and Kazoku has the best technology.
刚刚  我还真以为
For a second there, you had me convinced
你是想陪我打高尔夫
you actually wanted to play a round of golf with me
庆祝生日呢
for my birthday.
抱歉  盖瑞  只是...
I'm sorry, Gary. I just--
我真的很需要这显示屏
look, I really need this.
上回你让我帮忙...
Last time you came to me for help--
我不想让唐娜再折腾一次了
I won't let Donna go through that again.
这回不像上次  我保证
This isn't like last time, I promise you.
-哪不像  -完全不像
- How's it different? - It's completely different.
乔  项目负责人是他
Joe, he's running the project.
他在IBM干了十多年
He's got over a decade at IBM under his belt.
-乔·麦克米伦吗  -对
- Joe MacMillan? - Yeah.
唐娜总说他只会夸夸其谈
Donna keeps telling me he's all hat and no cattle.
不不  他真的很厉害
No, no, no, no. He's the real deal.
对天发誓
Honest to God.
而且我手下有一整个团队的工程师
And I got a whole team of engineers that are
在拼命工作
busting their asses for me.
你也认识约翰·博斯沃思
And you know John Bosworth.
卡迪夫是家实力雄厚的公司
I mean, Cardiff's a solid company.
日本人喜欢我
The Japs love me.
我让他们赚了不少钱
You know, I make 'em a bundle.
他们得见到你
They'll have to meet with you.
见不到人他们是不会做生意的
They don't do business without a face-to-face.
好  我会推掉所有的工作
Yeah, I'll clear my schedule.
谢谢
Thank you.
抱歉
Sorry.
这是去"明星舞会"的路线
And these are the directions to Big Star Ball
万一你决定要来呢
in case you decide to come.
我们去年举办了舞会
We had a ball last year.
你忘了我是纽约来的吗
Are you forgetting? I'm from New York.
我尽量吧
I'm trying.
-要我打给你父亲吗  -什么
- Do you want me to call your father? - What?
你父亲  他刚打来
Your father. You just missed him.
他要去香港  这周四会在达拉斯短暂停留
He has a layover this Thursday in Dallas on his way to Hong Kong.
他说住哪了吗
Did he say where he's staying?
凯瑞顿酒店
The Kerrington Hotel.
打电话告诉他一点在大堂酒吧见
Call him and tell him I'll meet him at the lobby bar at 1:00.
你这是干什么  不通知我就约见供应商
What are you doing, arranging a vendor meeting without me?
他们明早要回东京
They were headed back to Tokyo in the morning.
机不可失啊
It was now or never.
-不见  取消  -什么  不行
- Never. Cancel it. - What? No.
没时间跟你解释
I don't have time to explain this to you.
-取消  -你总和我要天上的月亮
- Just cancel it. - You keep asking me for the moon
我好不容易摘下来了  你却不要
and I finally get it for you and now you're saying no.
华族的屏幕怎么就月亮了
How is Kazoku's screen the moon?
他们研发出了领先液晶屏技术
They've developed cutting-edge LCD technology.
你要求电脑不超过12磅
You want our computer to be under 12 pounds
还得像公文包一样薄  这样一来就成了
and slim as a briefcase? This is how we do it.
他们会骗死我们
They'll gouge us.
我认识人  他能把价格压下来
I have a connection. He can get 'em down on price.
你哪来的关系
How do you have a connection?
这个圈子很小  总会认识什么人
It's a small industry. You meet people.
我约了7点在麦金尼大街的寿司店见面
Look, I'm meeting them at Sushi on McKinney at 7:00.
你去不去
Are you in or are you out?
IBM都不用液晶屏
IBM doesn't even make them with LCD screens.
把见面地点改到伍德森饭店
Change the reservation to Woodson's.
日本人来达拉斯不是为了吃寿司一样的
Japanese don't come to Dallas to have a shrimp cocktail
鸡尾冷虾  他们是来吃牛排的
dressed up like a sushi roll. They come for steak.
好主意
Good call.
干得好
Nice work.
怎么了
What?
你的评论  很逗
Your comments. They're funny.
小心点  我可能会把存档都交给你做
You be careful. I might ask you to document all my code.
看这个
Check this out...
不行  打印机只能打印文本
Oh, no, the printer only prints text.
你加入了图形模式吗
Wait, you added a graphics mode?
还有自动灰度图转换
And auto grayscale conversion?
厉害
Oh! Cool.
周五我们一群人要去看打车
Uh, Friday, a bunch of us are going to that KCYD car thing,
然后去吃晚饭  你想去吗
then to dinner if you're interested.
或许吧
Yeah, maybe.
活儿干得怎么样了
Now, how are we doing over here?
我干完了
I'm finished.
你在分工表上登记了吗
Did you check off your module on the flowchart?
没有  我都说我做完了
No, just told you I'm finished.
你还是得去签个名
Well, I still need you to put a check by your name.
这是规程
It's part of the protocol.
我在斯坦福商学院学到的
Learned it at Stanford B-School.
是废话学院吧
Does the B stand for bullshit?
有问题就来我办公室
If you have a problem, you can come by my office
我们像成年人一样好好讨论
and we can discuss it like adults.
没必要发火
No need to get your panties in a wad.
内裤
我没有穿内裤
Oh, I'm not wearing any panties.
让你的分工表见鬼去吧
But you can stick that in your flowchart.
你得把那混蛋弄走
You have to get rid of that tool.
-哪个  -我没开玩笑  他是个糟糕的经理
- Which one? - I'm not kidding. He's a terrible manager.
简直是舍大取小
He can't see the forest for the trees.
你得把他撵走
You have to get rid of him.
我不用做任何事  你得学着与人合作
I don't have to do anything. Learn to work with people.
他让编程最快的人去写驱动
He's assigning drivers to the fastest coders
却让笨蛋去写编译器  太没效率了
and compilers to the lunkheads. It's inefficient.
放过他吧  他压力很大
Cut him some slack. He's under a lot of pressure.
什么...我能应对这压力
What-- I could handle the pressure.
这很难想象吗
Why is that so crazy?
这么说吧  你不善交际
Let's see-- you're not exactly a people person.
你没有任何管理经验  甚至是工作经验
You have no management experience or any job experience, really.
你从大学辍学
You dropped out of college...
那是因为你求我  混蛋
Because you begged me, asshole.
而且缺乏专业精神
...and you lack professionalism.
合格的经理不会辱骂上级
A manager doesn't swear at his superior,
更不会开着门骂
certainly not with his office door open.
这样更专业一点了吗
Is that more professional?
如果我让你错以为
Look, if I've given you the impression
因为我们的关系
that because of this thing we've got going on
你可以享有特别待遇  那我向你道歉
that you're entitled to special treatment, I'm sorry.
卡梅伦  你干什么
Cameron, what are you doing?
我只是想彻底结束"我们的关系"
I'm just taking this little thing we've got going off the table.
也许这能让你清醒点
Maybe that'll wake you up.
我落了点东西在你公寓
Uh, I left some stuff at your apartment, so...
你可以告诉史蒂夫我明天再来上班
you can tell Steve I'll report for duty tomorrow.
我听说他们不指望西方人会鞠躬
I read that they don't expect Westerners to bow,
但认为你应当双手接过他们的名片
but you're supposed to receive their business cards with both hands.
以示尊重
It's a sign of respect.
我去过东京9次
I've been to Tokyo nine times.
我是戈登·克拉克  很高兴见到你们
Gordon Clark. It's a pleasure to meet you.
是我们的荣幸
The pleasure is ours.
-我是武田康彦  -谢谢
- Hirohiko Taketa. - Thank you.
我是武田康彦
Hirohiko Taketa.
"武田康彦  华族电子国际销售主管"
"Hirohiko Taketa, head of International Sales, Kazoku Electronics."
武田先生  谢谢您今晚前来
Mr. Taketa, thank you for being our guest tonight.
为了盖瑞·埃默森的女婿  在所不辞
We would do anything for the son-in-law of Gary Emerson.
我...是盖瑞的女婿
I-I-I'm Gary's son-in-law.
是
Oh, hai.
抱歉  希望我没吓到你
Oh, sorry. Hope I didn't scare you.
我是乔·麦克米伦
I'm Joe MacMillan.
我认识乔·麦克米伦
I know Joe MacMillan.
我是老的那个  他是我儿子
Senior. He's my son.
你知道乔什么时候回来吗
Do you know when Joe will be back?
不知道  他...你怎么进来的
Uh, no, he's-- how did you get in here?
我给管理员看了我的证件
I showed the super my license.
如果说话的腔调像模像样
You say something with the right authority,
一般就能如愿以偿
you generally get what you want.
真有意思
Huh, that's fascinating.
我只是过来拿我东西的
I'm just here to get my stuff.
这球棒是我给他买的
I bought this bat for him.
还花了好长时间教他如何正确挥棒
Spent hours teaching him how to swing correctly.
他没这方面天赋
He wasn't exactly a natural.
我不知道乔有女朋友
Didn't know Joe had a girlfriend.
我不是他女朋友
I'm not his girlfriend.
乔的确不是会交女朋友的那种
Well, Joe's not exactly the girlfriend type.
他做了什么让你那么生他的气
So, what did he do to make you so mad at him?
他又做了什么让你那么生他的气
What did he do to make you so mad at him?
他是这么跟你说的吗
Is that what he told you?
不是  他从未提起过你
No, he never talks about you.
但如果你得靠骗管理员才能进他公寓
But if you had to lie to the super to get into his apartment,
我猜你们俩关系并不是很好
I'm guessing you're not exactly chummy.
说得真对
Touch?
事实上  他下午放了我鸽子
Actually, he stood me up this afternoon.
也许我们可以边喝边聊
Maybe we could commiserate over a drink.
谢谢  但我得走了
Thanks, but I've got to get going.
约了人吗
Someone waiting for you?
嗯
Yeah.
见到你很高兴  你是
Well, it was nice to meet you, Miss--
你还没说你叫什么
you know, I never caught your name.
卡梅伦
Cameron.
不是卡梅伦·豪伊吧
Not Cameron Howe?
你怎么知道我名字的
How do you know my name?
我的手下回到纽约后
When my guys came back to New York,
都念念不忘一个叫卡梅伦·豪伊的天才
they couldn't stop talking about this prodigy named Cameron Howe.
-得了吧  -真的
- Right. - Oh, yes.
他们说你是当代的艾达·拉芙蕾丝
They said you're the modern Ada Lovelace.
明天我要搭乘20小时的航班
Tomorrow, I'm taking a 20-hour flight
和比尔·盖茨去香港  他肯定要唠叨个不停
to Hong Kong with Bill Gates and he's gonna talk circles around me and
我想喝一杯壮壮胆
I could use some liquid courage.
可我又不想一个人喝
I hate to drink alone.
别管我  我是想查查
Don't mind me, I'm just gonna check
今天天气什么样
the weather report on the local news.
真是工程杰作
No, but it's-- it's really an amazing work of engineering.
我只有一个问题  你们怎么做到放大屏幕
The one question I have is how do you scale this to a bigger size
而不让它模糊的
without the display blurring?
调高电压
Oh, we make the voltage higher.
调高5伏通常就够了
Five volts usually enough, yeah.
可是电压那么高  往屏幕上投射一个像素
But if you zap a pixel with a voltage that high,
周围的像素都会扭曲  那不就重影了吗
the adjacent pixels twist, too. Don't you get ghosting?
要是加上第三层微电容呢
What if you laid in a third layer of microcapacitors?
这种技术你们不是已经试验过了吗
Aren't you experimenting with that technology already?
索尼试过了
Sony is.
那样价钱更高
It would cost you more.
-也许  -我们定价不能过高
- Well, maybe-- - We can't drive up the price
导致失去竞争力  我们的提议是
till we're no longer competitive. Here's our offer.
降低你们每台显示器的利润
You take a lower margin on the individual screens,
但是最终的利润给你们分成
we'll give you a percentage of our profits on the back end.
我已经尽力了  而且说实话
It's the best I can do, and, frankly,
别的个人电脑厂家
I don't think you'll get a better deal
不会有更好的提议了
from another PC manufacturer.
-干杯  -干杯
- Kanpai. - Kanpai.
慢点
Easy.
还有谁卡在这个变态的过道迷宫里了吗
Is anyone else stuck in the maze of twisty little passages?
扔一件物品试试
Try dropping an item.
什么
What?
有个海盗袭击了我  把装备抢了
A pirate just pounced on me and stole my treasure.
不不不  你闭嘴
No, no, no, no, you shut up!
你全家都语法错误
You have bad grammar.
你跟我走
You, come with me.
-我吗  -是你
- Me? - Yeah, you.
随便谁  所有人
Any of you. All of you.
快点  都进来
Get your asses in here, come on.
快点
Come on.
过来  进来
Come here, get in.
我他妈怎么从这洞里出去
How the hell do I get out of this godforsaken cave?
很期待与你合作
Really looking forward to working with you.
是
Hai.
做销售的不理解我们的工作
And the sales guys, they don't get what we do.
没法体会其中的艺术
You know, the artistry that's involved.
他们只在乎利润
All they care about's profit.
比如我岳父
Take my father-in-law.
你仔细翻过《刀锋》吗
Have you ever even looked through the "Razor's Edge"?
那家伙净卖些次品
I mean, you wouldn't believe the schlock that guy sells.
次品  很差的东西
Schlock, you know, like stupid stuff.
是
Hai.
次品
Schlock.
我看你包上有空军的徽章
I noticed an Air Force pin on your backpack.
-你爸爸的吗  -嗯
- Your father's? - Yeah.
越战吗
Vietnam?
直升机机工长
Helicopter crew chief.
那活儿不好干
Tough job.
太平洋战争时  我是海军军官
I was a naval officer in the Pacific.
没想到如今我每月都要飞去东京
If anyone had told me one day I'd be flying to Tokyo
低头哈腰...
every month and bowing to them...
你什么时候开始在IBM工作的
So, when did you start working for IBM?
1945年我被招去研发马克一号Oh, they recruited me in 1945 to work on the Mark I.
美国第一部大尺度自动数位电脑  被认为是第一部万用型计算机
和葛丽丝·霍普一起吗  你见到她了
With Grace Hopper? Did you meet her?
计算机科学家  世界最早一批的程式设计师之一
当然
Oh, sure.
-机器真的重达四吨吗  -五吨
- Did it really weigh four tons? - Five.
我们海军用它来计算炮弹发射
We used it in the Navy to calculate artillery firing.
当时我就知道  我今后要去蓝色巨人工作
I knew right then I wanted to work for Big Blue when I got out.
全球最棒的公司
Best company in the world.
我还是不明白乔为什么要离开公司
And I still don't understand what possessed Joe to leave.
我很惊讶你拒绝了我们
I was surprised you turned us down.
你本可以成为下一个葛丽丝·霍普
You could've been the next Grace Hopper.
现在  你眼看就要成为
Instead, you're in line to
一个无人会知晓的程序员
be another programmer no one remembers.
我的天呐  你说得对
Oh, my God, you're right.
我真不该去给全新的电脑写软件
Yeah, instead of writing software for a brand-new machine,
而是该去给
I could've been getting coffee for the guy
替写软件的人暖座的人端咖啡
who warms the seat for the guy who writes the software.
我怎么想的啊
What was I thinking?
对不起  我太过分了
Yeah, I'm sorry. That was out of line.
我不是在生你的气
You're not the one I'm angry at.
父子关系总是很难办
It's a tricky thing, fathers and sons.
你爸爸很幸运有个女儿
Your dad's lucky to have a daughter.
我打赌他来见你的话  你肯定不会让他空等
I bet you'd never stand him up if he came to see you.
天呐  对不起
Oh, God, I'm sorry.
他没能活着回来  对吧
He didn't make it back, did he?
你当时肯定连十岁都不到
You couldn't have been more than 10 years old at the time.
我...失陪了
I-- excuse me.
他们付了账单
They picked up the check.
你醉到看不出来这代表他们不跟我们合作了吗
Are you too drunk to comprehend that means they're done with us?
我就不该让你来
I should never have let you come.
让我来  这笔生意是我安排的
Let me come? I arranged this deal.
不  是盖瑞安排的  而你却侮辱他
No, Gary did, and then you insulted him.
说你自己岳父的坏话
Nothing says, "Don't trust us"
就等于是告诉别人"别相信我们"
quite like bad-mouthing your own father-in-law.
你爸爸在IBM工作
Look, your father works at IBM
你整天到处
and you shit on them all the time
-说他们坏话  -没跟日本人说
- to everyone. - Not to the Japanese.
技术你是厉害
Look, you may be good with a soldering iron,
但谈生意
but when it comes to business,
考虑大局  你什么都不懂
the big picture, you have no idea.
跟那个疯女人上床的可不是我
Hey, hey. I'm not the one screwing "Cuckoo for Cocoa Puffs."
-别提她  -这事将来肯定要毁了我们
- Leave her out of this. - Like that's not gonna blow up in our face!
回去跟其他工作人员一起待着吧
Go back to your workstation with the rest of the grunts.
我明早解决这个问题
I'll fix this in the morning.
怎么解决  凭你的三寸不烂之舌吗
With what, Joe, your words?
唐娜说得对  你只会夸夸其谈
Donna was right. You're all hat and no cattle.
那你怎么不和唐娜一起搭建个电脑
Why don't you build a computer with Donna?
对了  你们失败了
Oh, wait, you tried that.
你爸爸会杀了我的
Your dad's gonna kill me.
肯定没你想得那么糟
Well, I bet it wasn't as bad as you think.
就是这么糟
Look, I'm telling you, it was.
我这次真的搞砸了
I really screwed the pooch this time.
肯定会有解决方法的
Well, I'm sure it'll work out somehow.
亲爱的  我烤箱里还烤着派呢
Oh, honey, I've got pies in the oven.
-等你回家我们再谈吧  -好吧
- We can talk more about this when you get home. - Okay.
好吧  那我...
Okay, yeah, I'll--
怎么了  戈登
What, Gordon?
我是亨特
Uh, it's Hunt.
我打得不是时候吗
Am I catching you at a bad time?
不不不  时候很好
No, no, no. It's wonderful.
我是说  有事吗
I mean... what's up?
我打给你是因为
Well, the reason I'm calling is 'cause
我看了你的另一份报告
I had a chance to go over that other report of yours,
写得很好
and I wanna say I was really impressed.
很高兴你能这么积极
I love that you took the initiative.
谢谢
Well, thank you.
那个
Listen...
我想跟你道歉  那天不该冲你发火
I wanted to apologize for snapping at you the other day.
上边骂了我  没办法
I was getting hammered from upstairs and, what can I say?
但我不该拿你撒气
I shouldn't have taken it out on you.
没事的
Oh, it's no big deal, really. I just
我回家还吼我女儿了呢
yelled at my kids when I got home.
孩子不就干这个用的吗
Well, that's what they're there for.
我不想再叨扰
Well, I don't want to cut into your evening
你晚上休息了
any more than I already have.
没有  我在做桃子派呢
Oh, no, I'm just making some peach pies
给我父母烧烤派对准备的
for my parents' barbecue.
桃子派啊
Peach pies?
我可喜欢了
I love peach pie.
你往面团里掺伏特加吗
Do you put vodka in your dough?
伏特加
Vodka?
我奶奶  她会
My granny, she used to
放一半水  一半伏特加
substitute half the water for a shot of vodka.
她说这样硬皮就不会因为水果馅
She said it kept the crust from getting all soggy
而变得软绵绵的
from the fruit filling.
我倒觉得她是为万一派做得不好
I think she did it so if her pie didn't turn out,
大家也都醉醺醺的  尝不出来
everyone would be too drunk to notice.
她听上去好机智啊
Oh, well, she sounds like a smart lady.
是啊  她最好了
Yeah, she was the best.
那...
Well, I...
就不打扰你做派了
better let you get back to bakin'.
如果还有剩  回头给我拿点来吧
If you have any left over, feel free to save me a slice.
好啊  明天见
Okay. I'll see you tomorrow.
晚安  唐娜
Good night, Donna.
能让他早上再找你吗  现在不是时候
Can he call you in the morning? Now's not a really good time.
是急事
It's kinda urgent.
亲爱的  能到门口来一下吗
Sweetheart, can you come to the door for a second?
我们在主持比赛之夜
We're hosting game night.
真有趣
Fun.
他喝醉了
He's drunk.
怎么回事
What happened?
你没事吧
Are you okay?
-抱歉  我一般不...  -没事的
- Sorry, I don't usually... - No, it's perfectly all right.
我猜你工作压力一定很大
I think you're under a lot of stress at work.
乔看错你了
Joe's all wrong about you.
乔的错误有很多
Joe's wrong about a lot of things.
他什么时候会放弃这一切啊
How close is he to giving up on all this?
不好说  他看上去挺有决心的
I don't know. He's pretty determined.
他刚刚背着我雇了一堆程序员
He just hired a whole team of programmers
和一个经理
and a manager behind my back.
气死我了
Really pissed me off.
我真不想这么说  但乔就这样
I hate to say it, but that sounds like Joe.
他在IBM也这么干过吗
Did he pull this at IBM?
总是如此
All the time.
你知道他在IBM的三次升职是怎么得到的吗
You know how he got his three promotions at IBM?
强取
He took them.
一次  他对一位上司撒谎
One time, he actually lied to a supervisor--
那人都跟我们干了20年了
guy who'd been with us for over 20 years--
跟他说他就要被解雇了
warned him that he was going to be let go
强烈建议他自己辞职
and then strongly suggested that he tender his resignation to
以保住面子
maintain his dignity.
那可怜人就信了
Poor guy believed him.
如果说话的腔调像模像样
Well, if you say something with the right authority,
一般就能如愿以偿
you generally get what you want.
你真是满嘴胡话
You're so full of shit.
你真觉得我就会乖乖
What, did you actually think I was gonna roll over
跑去告诉乔你是个大好人吗
and just tell Joe what a great guy you were?
你俩都是混蛋
You're both disgusting.
我看你并不清楚
I don't think you understand
你是跟什么样的人搅在了一起
who you've gotten into bed with.
他迟早会毁了一切
It's only a matter of time until he blows everything up.
他向来如此
He always does.
-那你肯定最清楚了  -我给了他一切
- Well, you would know. - I gave him the world...
他却羞辱我
and he spat in my face.
他觉得一切都该是他的
He thinks everything belongs to him...
也包括你
you included.
等你想明白了来找我吧
For when you figure that out.
肖邦  《幻想即兴曲》
Impromptu No.4 In C Sharp Minor, Op.66 "Fantaisie-Impromptu"
一会儿就走
I'll only be a minute.
我们昨晚犯了错
We made a mistake last night.
我们冒犯了你们  为此  我十分抱歉
We offended you, and for that, I am sorry.
克拉克先生没脸来见你们
Mr. Clark was too ashamed to come,
所以我答应会替他表示道歉
so I promised I would apologize on his behalf
他很抱歉他喝醉了  还让你们觉得
for getting drunk, for giving the impression
他不尊重他的岳父
that he doesn't respect his father-in-law,
本来就是他岳父好心替我们安排了这次见面
the man who was gracious enough to put us into contact with you.
但其实他绝无轻慢的意思
That is not the case. Not for him,
我更没有
and certainly not for me
我可以毫不夸张地说
I'm m not exaggeratg when I say
如果不是我父亲  我不会有今日的成就
that I wouldn't be where I am today if it weren't for my father.
我从他母校一毕业
The day I graduated from his alma mater,
他就带我进了他的公司  IBM
he brought me into his company, IBM.
他教会了我一切一切
He taught me the ropes. He taught me everything I know.
他要我全力以赴
He told me to swing for the fences
从此我就一直在努力
and I've never stopped swinging.
我知道这么跑来很冒险
I know it's a risk showing up like this,
但我愿尽一切努力
but I will do anything
争取让你们再考虑跟我们合作
to make you reconsider being in business with us.
太好了
Excellent.
先生
Sir?
您落下了杂志
You forgot your magazine.
我看完了
I'm done with that.
别费事了
Oh, don't bother.
-你被解雇了  -你说什么
- You're fired. - Excuse you?
倒不是因为你是个混蛋  虽然你的确是
Oh, and it's not 'cause you're a tool, which you are.
你不能解雇我  我是你上司
You can't fire me. I'm your boss.
你想在11周内把所有软件编好
Do you want all your software programmed in 11 weeks
而且开销减半吗
for half of what you're spending?
这是陷阱问题吗
Is this a trick question?
布鲁克斯法则  《人月神话》Brooks' Law, "The Mythical Man-Month."
IBM System/360系统之父佛瑞德·布鲁克斯
被誉为软件领域的圣经
我大学期间读的唯一一本有用的书
The one useful book I read in college.
布鲁克斯说  为了加快
Brooks said that adding programmers
软件项目的进程而多找程序员只会适得其反
to speed up a software project only makes it later.
她的态度很有问题
She's got a real attitude problem.
对了  我要接手史蒂夫的工作
Oh, also, I'm taking over Steve's job.
瞧见了吧
See what I mean?
你怎么知道该留哪个程序员
How would you know which programmers to keep?
你知道他们都叫什么吗
Do you even know their names?
程序猿们  都过来
Coder monkeys, come here.
你们昨晚多少人玩了一晚上《巨洞冒险》
How many of you got sucked into "Adventure" last night?
我就知道  她在搞破坏  乔
I knew it. She's sabotaging the project, Joe.
出于好奇  你们多少人
Okay, just curious-- how many of you figured out
搞清楚了在水坝那里按按钮的顺序
what order to push the buttons in at the dam?
你们多少人走出洞穴是靠修改源代码
And how many of you got out of the cave by breaking the code?
我当时急着赶回家喂猫
I had to get home to feed my cat.
你们都用了什么后门
Which back doors did you use?
-"Xyzzy"  -"Plover"
- "Xyzzy." - "Plover."
-"Plugh"  -好吧
- "Plugh." - Okay.
莱夫  悠悠球  和其他作弊的
Lev, Yo-Yo, the rest of you guys who cheated,
你们工作保住了
you get to keep your jobs.
剩下那些玩得正大光明的
Those of you who played fair and square,
多谢  但你们可以回家了
thank you very much, but you can go home.
解释一下
Explain.
老实玩游戏的人得会解谜
To play an honest game, you have to be good at solving puzzles.
作弊的人得会破解代码
But to cheat, you have to be great at solving code.
这些人才是我团队需要的人
Those are the guys I need on my team--
会破解源代码  找到后门
the ones who can break into the code, find the back doors,
找到"Plover"  "Xyzzy"
figure out "Plover" and "Xyzzy"
和"Fee Fie Foe Foo"达到目的的人
and "Fee Fie Foe Foo" to get it done.
-你找到"Fee Fie Foe Foo"了吗  -没有
- Did you find "Fee Fie Foe Foo"? - No.
史蒂夫  我会给你写封好推荐信的
Steve, I'll write you a nice letter of recommendation.
我最初听说要在戈登·克拉克手下干的时候
When I first heard I'd be working for Gordon Clark,
我都不确定他是否熟悉主板
I wasn't sure he even knew his way around a motherboard.
事实无数次证明是我想错了
Well, I've been proven wrong a hundred times over,
而今天我对他的崇敬
and, today, my respect for this guy
又达到了新的境界
has been taken to a whole new level.
敬戈登  干得漂亮
To Gordo for kicking ass and taking names.
敬戈登
To Gordo.
谢了  戈登  干得真好
Thanks, Gordon. Good job, buddy.
看来你把液晶屏的好消息跟他们说了
Hey, I see you told them the good news about the LCD screen.
是啊  大家都很激动
Yeah, everyone's excited.
很好  我以为你没收到我的消息呢
Good, I thought maybe you didn't get my message.
我收到了
No, I did.
我以为你会去我办公室
Figured you'd come by my office.
我有事
I've got work to do.
你不觉得你该跟我道声谢吗
Don't you think you owe me a thank-you?
不  乔  我不觉得
No, Joe. Actually, I don't.
好吧
Right.
我不过就是救了你的小命  这笔生意
I only saved your ass, the deal,
和你跟你岳父的关系
and your relationship with your father-in-law.
戈登跟你们说他差点毁了这笔生意的事了吗
Gordon tell you how he almost tanked the deal?
乔  别说了
Joe, don't.
首先  他喝了8杯威士忌
First, he does eight shots of whiskey
不想被日本人比下去  大错误
trying to keep up with the Japanese-- huge mistake.
这下他喝醉了  跟着总工程师...
So now he's wasted and he follows the chief engineer into--
乔  我真不想戳破实情
Joe, I hate to bust your bubble,
但你没挽救下什么
but you didn't save a damn thing.
是盖瑞  我跑去他家
Gary did after I went to his house and asked him--
苦苦哀求他
no, I begged him-- got down on my knees
说服他们重新考虑
to convince them to reconsider.
你赶去酒店之前生意就谈好了
The deal was done before you ever got to the hotel.
你要他的号码  给他道个谢吗
Do you want his phone number to thank him?
你们先走吧
Look, you guys take off.
我得想想怎么解决过热的问题
I'll figure out the heating problem.
卡梅伦
Cameron...
你待会儿去保龄球馆吗
are you going to this bowling alley thing later?
不知道  听上去挺没劲
I don't know. It sounds dumb,
但有些程序员会去
but some of the coders are going.
达拉斯的文化活动真令人瞠目
It's amazing what passes for culture in Dallas.
我发现你昨晚把自己的东西从我公寓拿走了
I saw you took your stuff out of my apartment last night.
还拿了不属于你的东西
And a few things that don't belong to you.
什么东西
What things?
别误会  我觉得
Don't get me wrong, I think it's sweet
你想看《华尔街季刊》
that you wanted to read the article
那篇文章挺可爱的
in the "Wall Street Quarterly."
我没拿
I didn't take it.
在乎我们的项目没什么丢人的
There's no shame in caring about our project.
我只是想要回来  好寄给分销商
I just need it back so I can send it to some retailers.
你爸去过你公寓
Your dad came by the apartment.
是他拿的
He took it.
你跟他谈了吗
Did you talk to him?
我没待多久
Uh, I didn't stay long.
他们还在等我
The guys are waiting for me.
我们刚把这辆崭新的1983款达特桑280ZX
We just drove this spanking new 1983 Datsun 280ZX
从待售车场开过来
off the lot.
日本人自称他们的车比我们的结实
Now, the Japs say their cars are stronger than ours.
我们瞧瞧吧
We're gonna see about that.
来吧  伙计们  5美元一棍
Step up, folks. It's only $5 a swing.
我们要一直待到那辆车跟薄煎饼一样扁
We're gonna stay here until that sucker is flat as a pancake.
来吧  姑娘们
Come on up here, ladies!
人人影视
倾情奉献
翻译
磁芯章鱼X
木浅薰
翻译
某豚
冬麟
翻译
七七
somehacker
翻译
小花豆
草草
时间轴
Kallen 芒果树叶
特效
宝宝
电脑狂人
第一季
第五集
校对&总监
草草
后期
饿得慌